Gabriele Marini

Italian, 12th of September 1992
giaga7@gmail.com
marinig@student.unimelb.edu.au
(+61) 481149376

Melbourne, Australia

https://gmarini.com Linkedln: @gabryxx7 GitHub: @gabryxx7

Summary

Third year PhD Candidate at the University of Melbourne, sponsored by CSIRO-Data61. My research focuses on indoor localisation, sensors and data modeling. I am very passionate about computer science in general and especially ubiquitous computing and sensors. I often dabble in 3D graphics and game development (Unity mostly), web development (full stack) and data science (Python + R).

Education

PhD in Computing and Information Systems

May 2018 - Ongoing

University of Melbourne. Melbourne, Australia

Third year PhD Candidate. Expected graduation: June 2022

Top-Up Scholarship PhD Candidate

May 2018 - Nov 2021

CSIRO - Data61. Melbourne, Australia Supervised by Raja Jurdak and Brano Kusy.

MSc in Computer Science (Laurea Magistrale)

Jun 2017

Universitá degli Studi di Pisa. Pisa, Italy

Final grade: 110/110 cum laude

Master's Thesis: Injection of an efficient scripting language in a large C++ framework for fully

immersive Virtual Environments

BSc in Computer Science

Jul 2014

Universitá degli Studi di Cagliari (Laurea Triennale). Cagliari, Italy

Final grade: 110/110 cum laude

Bachelor's Thesis: An Interactive Shoes Showcase

Experience

Data Science Research Intern

Jun 2021 - Sep 2021

Nokia Bell Labs. (Remote) Cambridge, UK

Set up an RFID based indoor localization system and proxemics tracker. Deployment did not go through due to COVID limitations. The project got repurposed to a Data Science related work. We extracted and analysed a corpus of Slack messages through NLP tools, Social Network Analysis with some Network Metrics. We then built a model to detect leadership in teams through these metrics without prior knowledge about the group's hierarchy.

Tutor/Demonstrator

Jul 2018 - Ongoing

University of Melbourne. Melbourne, Australia

I have been teaching at least one subject each semester during my PhD. Teaching and tutoring also included material creation, rubrics writing as well as marking of assignments, projects and final exams:

- INFO20005 (2021, 2022): UI Development (Front-End Development with HTML, CSS and JS)
- INFO90003 (2020): Designing Novel Interaction (Tangible interactions with Arduino and Raspberry Pi)
- COMP30019 (2018, 2019 and 2020): Computer Graphics and Interaction (With Unity 3D, C# and HLSL)
- SWEN20003 (2019 taught at the International House): Object Oriented Software Development (In Java)

Trainees Program Chair

Sep 2020 - Jun 2021

NHMRC Centre of Research Excellence (CRE) in Digital Technology to Transform Chronic Disease Outcomes. Melbourne, Australia

I have lead the group of PhD students trainees and was in charge of setting up and conducting the monthly meetings and reporting back to the Chief Investigators. I also took part in the organization

of workshops, seminars and retreats for the group.

PhD Candidate May 2018 - Ongoing

University of Melbourne. Melbourne, Australia

- Treasurer of the CIS Research Students Association (CIS-GReS)
- Equipment manager for the IDL (now HCI) lab
- Floor Warden for the CIS department

Consultant Oct 2017 - Feb 2018

European Central Bank (ECB). Frankfurt, Germany

I worked on the long-term IReF project implementing an online survey to be sent out to all the banks in Europe. Besides that, I offered technical support for IT-related matters (Python scripts, WordPress websites management, Javascript, VBA, SQL)

Research Assistant Jun 2017 - Oct 2017

TeCIP Institute, Scuola Superiore Sant'Anna. Pisa, Italy

I worked mostly on robot vision and Hand-Eye camera robot calibration. I also developed part of the HMI (C#, MySQL) with a 3D Viewer of the robotic arm with inverse kinematics

Intern Oct 2016 - Jun 2017

VRMedia - Scuola Superiore Sant'Anna. Pisa, Italy

I developed and wrote my master thesis under the supervision of Prof. Franco Tecchia.

Technical skills

Programming Languages: C++, C#, C, PHP, Java, Python

Data Analysis/Visualisation: R, Python, Javascript (and NodeJS), SQL, MySQL, MatLab

Web Development: HTML, CSS, Javascript (and NodeJS), PHP Markup Languages: Latex, Markdown, YAML, HTML, XML, JSON

Tools/Framework: Many IDEs and notebooks such as PyCharm, Eclipse, Jupyter, RStudio, Unity3D,

Photoshop, Blender, WordPress

Talks

• Brainstorming Workshop

NHMRC CRE 2021

• Masterclass in Photography for HCI Research

University of Melbourne, April 2021

• Towards Context-Free Semantic Localization

UbiComp, London, UK, Sep 2019

• Towards Indoor Localization Analytics for Modelling Flow of Movements Doctoral Colloquium, London, UK, Sep 2019

• Flow-Optimisation based on indoor localisation

Data61/CSIRO, Aug 2019

• Reliable Operating Rooms

Northern Health, Melbourne, Nov 2018

• Seminar on Indoor Localisation for supporting decision-making University of Melbourne, Nov 2018

PhD Confirmation Seminar - Flow Optimization based on indoor localization

University of

Melbourne, Jun 2018

Projects

Semantic Indoor Localisation, PhD Research Project

Supervisor: Prof. Vassilis Kostakos

Emotion Recognition with Affectiva, Side project at UniMelb

Developed as a way of interacting with PCs through emotions and facial expressions, we used the Affectiva SDK and C# on Windows or Java on Android.

Injection of a scripting language into the Unreal Engine, Master thesis

Supervisor: Prof. Franco Tecchia

MeshLabJS Texture and .zip support, Final project

Supervisor: Prof. Paolo Cignoni

Interactive shoes showcase. Bachelors thesis

Supervisor: Prof. Riccardo Scateni

Languages

- Italian, Native speaker
- English, Fluent, TOEFL (2017): 112 (C2)
- Spanish, Intermediate

Certificates

MTC CD MILL TO IN CONTRACT COLUMN	NI 0010
• MTC-GR - Melbourne Teaching Certificate for Graduate Research	Nov 2019
• WWCC - Working With Children Certificate	Feb 2019
• UniMelb Tutor Development Program	Jun 2018
• RIOT - Research Integrity Online Training	Jun 2018
• TOEFL 112/120 (Reading: 28, Listening: 28, Speaking: 26, Writing: 30)	Sep 2017
DADI O Wata Di tauliana	

• PADI - Open Water Diving License

Awards

- PhD Scholarship awarded by CSIRO Data61
- Top graduates award awarded by Universitá di Pisa
- Top graduates award awarded by ERSU Cagliari

Relevant courses

- Distinguished Project Award: INFO90003 2019 Designing Novel Interaction
- Research Methods COMP90044
- Computer Graphics
- Linear Algebra
- Introduction to Robotics Virtual Environments
- Programming Languages and Compilers
- Advanced Databases
- Advanced Programming
- Advanced Algorithms

Additional Activities

- Attended CHI 2021 remotely
- SV (Student Volunteer) at UbiComp 2020 Online
- Doctoral Colloquium and Workshop presenter at UbiComp 2019 in London, UK
- SV (Student Volunteer) at UbiComp 2019 in London, UK
- Open Day Volunteer at the University of Melbourne, Australia
- SV (Student Volunteer) and attendee at OzCHI 2018 in Melbourne, Australia
- Attended UbiComp 2018 in Singapore

Extras

- Photographer (landscape, astro-photography, aerial and events such as graduations or weddings)
- Traveller and backpacker
- Long distance and open water swimmer

Publications

- 1. <u>G. Marini</u>, B. Tag, J. Goncalves, E. Velloso, R. Jurdak, V. Kostakos. Measuring Mobility and Room Occupancy in Clinical Settings: System Development and Implementation, DOI: 10.2196/19874
- 2. <u>G. Marini</u>. Towards indoor localisation analytics for modelling flows of movements. 2019. International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing Adjunct (UbiComp '19 Adjunct) 377–382. doi:10.1145/3341162.3349306
- G. Marini, J. Gonçalves, E. Velloso, R. Jurdak, and V. Kostakos. 2019. Towards context-free semantic localisation. International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing Adjunct (UbiComp '19 Adjunct), 584–591. doi: 10.1145/3341162.3349329.
- 4. Northern Health gets its teeth into patient flow. 2019. VicHealth [URL]
- W. Jiang, G. Marini, N. Berkel, Z. Sarsenbayeva, Z. Tan, C. Luo, X. He, T. Dingler, J. Goncalves, Y. Kawahara, V. Kostakos. 2019. Probing Sucrose Contents in Everyday Drinks Using Miniaturized Near-Infrared Spectroscopy Scanners. Proceedings of the ACM on Interactive, Mobile, Wearable and Ubiquitous Technologies (IMWUT), 3(4), 136:1–136:25. doi: 10.1145/3369834. [ERA: A*].
- 6. W. Jiang, G. Marini, N. Berkel, Z. Sarsenbayeva, C. Luo, X. He, T. Dingler, Y. Kawahara, V. Kostakos. 2018. A Mobile Scanner for Probing Liquid Samples in Everyday Settings. 19 International Joint

- Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing Adjunct (UbiComp Adjunct). ACM, 1172–1177. doi: 10.1145/3267305.3274764.
- 7. Z. Sarsenbayeva, <u>G. Marini</u>, N. van Berkel, C. Luo, W. Jiang, K. Yang, G. Wadley, T. Dingler, V. Kostakos, J. Goncalves, "Does Smartphone Use Drive our Emotions or vice versa? A Causal Analysis", in Proceedings of ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI'20), 2020, to appear.
- 8. D. Hettiachchi, Z. Sarsenbayeva, F. Allison, N. van Berkel, T. Dingler, <u>G. Marini</u>, V. Kostakos, J. Goncalves, ""Hi! I am the Crowd Tasker" Crowdsourcing through Digital Voice Assistants", in Proceedings of ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI'20), 2020, to appear.